Finding Aid for the Paul Jordan Smith Papers LSC.0267
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscript Material by Paul Jordan Smith
  - Trends in Seventeenth Century Prose. Los Angeles, 1950-1951. (Box 31)
    - Student paper. The Treatment of Religion in the Utopian Literature of the Sixteenth and Seventeenth Centuries by J. Monteverde., 20 leaves, typescript. (Box 31, Folder 7)
      With this: Letter to Monteverde from Paul Jordan Smith. [Los Angeles, ca. 1951] 1 item (1 leaf).
  - The American Historical Novel. Los Angeles, 1958-1961. (Box 31)
    English X112AB, UCLA extension course taught by Paul Jordan Smith.
    - Bulletins, memos, procedures., 5 items. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Enrollment and parking applications., ca. 40 items. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Enrollment., 7 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Examination questions., 6 items. Typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Lecture #1., 17 leaves, Holograph. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Lecture #1., 4 leaves, typescript. (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Transcribed lecture notes.
    - Lecture #2., 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Lecture #2., 10 leaves, typescript. (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Lecture #3., 16 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Lecture #4., 18 leaves, Holograph. (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Lecture #5., 22 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Lecture #6., 1 leaf, typescript. (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Lecture #7., 10 leaves, Holograph, typescript and mimeo. (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Lecture #8., 12 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Lecture #9., 10 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Lecture #10., 15 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Lecture #11., 21 leaves, typescript, holograph and mimeo. (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Lecture #12., 14 leaves, Holograph. (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Lecture #13., 7 leaves, Holograph. (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Lecture #14., 4 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Lecture #15., 10 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Notes., 20 leaves, Holograph, typescript and mimeo. (Box 31, Folder 29)
      With this Clippings. 2 items.
    - Proposed book on the American historical novel by Paul Jordan Smith. [Los Angeles], 1961. (Box 31)
      - --Introduction., 6 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 31, Folder 30)
        With this letter to Dorothy Wysor from Jordan re title of proposed book. n.p., December 28, 1961. 1 leaf, Holograph.
      - --Introduction., 7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 31, Folder 31)
        Tentatively titled Challenge to Courage: Some Significant Chapters of American History as Seen by Historical Novelists.
      - --Notes., 11 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 31, Folder 32)
      - --Notes for Chapter 1., 9 leaves, typescript, holograph and mimeo. (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Reading list., 10 items. Typescript, holograph and mimeo. (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Recommended reading., 1 item (2 leaves) Typescript. (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - The Anatomy of Melancholy by Robert Burton, now for the first time with the Latin completely given in translation and embodied in an all-English text, edited by Floyd Dell and Paul Jordan Smith... New York, Farrar & Rinehart, incorporated [c, 1927]. (Box 32)
    - Galley proofs., ca. 500 leaves. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Prefatory note., 1 leaf, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Introduction., 13 leaves, Holograph. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Introduction., 7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Notes., 5 leaves, typescript and printed. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Outline., 5 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Bibliographia Burtoniana. A study of Robert Burton's Anatomy of Melancholy with a bibliography of Burton's writings by Paul Jordan Smith. Stanford University, Stanford University Press, 1931. (Box 33)
    - Preface., 9 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      With bibliographical notes.
    - Order of arrangement., 9 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon. In blue folder. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      With notes.
    - Bibliographia Melancholia., 65 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Illustrations., 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Galleys., 8 leaves. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Notes., 10 leaves, typescript, holograph and printed. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Transcription of Burton-Smythe letter (1648)., 3 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 33, Folder 7)
      See Also: Box 26, Footnote Smith.
    - Correspondence. v.p, 1931.; 2 items (5 leaves). (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Letters to the editor of the Saturday Review from Vincent Starrett and Gordon Ray Young refuting criticism of the Bibliographia Burtoniana.
  - Robert Burton's Philosophaster with an English translation of the same. (Box 33)
    Together with his other minor writings in prose and verse; the translation, introductions and notes by Paul Jordan Smith. Stanford University Press, California, Stanford University Press; H. Milford, Oxford University Press, 1931.
    - Notes., 4 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Notes. Acts 1-5., 10 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Preface., 5 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Prologue., 2 leaves, Holograph. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Manuscript., 49 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Manuscript., ca. 175 leaves, typescript carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Argument and Act 1., 34 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Act 1, scene 4., 2 leaves, typescript. (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Act 2., 25 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Act 3., 20 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Act 4., 31 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Act 5., 28 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Robert Burton's poems., 30 leaves, typescript. (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Programs. Los Angeles, January 17, 1930.; 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 22)
      Philosophaster was performed at UCLA by members of Chi Delta Phi.
  - Cables of Cobwebs, by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Lieber & Lewis, 1923. (Box 34)
    - --Manuscript. Claremont, California, 1921-1922.; 893 leaves, Holograph. (Box 34)
      Second draft.
      Note this mss. contains 30,000 words concerning episodes rejected by the publisher. PJS In brown cloth box.
    - Manuscript. Claremont, California, 1921.; ca. 430 leaves, typescript. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Second draft., ca. 120 leaves, typescript carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Suppressed part of Cables of Cobwebs.
    - Third draft, uncorrected., ca. 370 leaves, typescript and typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 39., 12 leaves, Holograph. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 39-42., 39 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 40., 8 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 43., 13 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 44., 7 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 45-[46]., 18 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 46., 5 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 47., 31 leaves, Holograph. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Alternate final chapter., 9 leaves, typescript. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Deleted pages., 5 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Reviews., 1922-1923.; 3 items. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - For the Love of Books; the Adventures of an Impecunious Collector, by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Oxford University Press, 1934. (Box 36)
    - Magic mirrors: Being the Apologies, Reflections and Fanfaronades of an Impecunious Book-Collector by Paul Jordan Smith. Los Angeles, 1933(?).; ca. 200 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Alternate titles: Book-worm's wallett; Bookman's wallet.
    - Magick Mirrours: Being the Apologies, Reflections, and Fanfaronades of an Impecunious Book-Collector. Paul Jordan Smith., ca. 275 leaves, typescript and holograph. Bound. (Box 36, Folder 2)
      Uncorrected copy. Alternate title: Book-Worm's Wallet.
    - On Discovering Items in Footnotes., ca. 40 of 100 leaves, in blue composition notebook. (Box 36, Folder 3)
      Later retitled Footnote Finds and Follies.
    - Footnote Finds and Follies. Chapter 4., 31 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Illustrations., 11 items. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence., 3 items (4 leaves). (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Galleys., ca. 100 leaves. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Nomad, by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Minton, Balch & Company, 1925. (Box 37)
    - Nomad: A Fantasy. Original draft. Claremont, California, 1920s(?).; 167 leaves, and 5 composition books containing final chapters,ca. 25 leaves, each. Typescript and holograph. In brown leather case. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      With letter of transmittal from Paul Jordan Smith to Jake Zeitlin. Hollywood, December 25, 1930. 1 item (2 leaves) Holograph.
      Gift of Jacob Zeitlin.
    - Table of contents., 1 leaf, typescript and holograph. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Nomad: A Fantasy by Paul Jordan Smith. [Claremont], 1920s(?).; 70 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - [Chapter 10] A Ghost Dance in a Village Graveyard. Claremont, 1920s(?).; 37pp. in bound composition book. Holograph. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Illustrations., 3 items. Pen and ink drawings of a cat. (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Used as tailpiece illustration.
    - Ephemera., 2 items. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - On Strange Altars, by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Albert & Charles Boni, 1924. (Box 37)
    SEE ALSO: pp.37-43.
    - Neo-Paganism., 8 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Ephemera., 2 items. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Poetry from Hidden Springs. Garden City, New York, Doubleday & Company, Incorporated, 1962. (Box 38)
    - Notes. [Los Angeles], 1960.; 17 leaves, Holograph and typescript. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Poems by Ruth Guthrie [Harding] Burton. n.p., 1960-1961.; 31 leaves, typescript. (Box 38, Folder 2)
      With this: correspondence to Paul Jordan Smith from Ruth Guthrie [Harding] Burton. 2 items (2 leaves, and 2 env.).
    - Manuscript. [Los Angeles,., 1960-1961]; ca. 200 leaves, typescript. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Reader's galleys, 1961.; ca. 90 leaves. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Reader's pages, 1961.; ca. 90 leaves. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Final galley proof, 1961.; ca. 90 leaves. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Poems for proposed second edition of Poetry from hidden springs., 2 leaves, typescript. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Some Rabelaisian Fauncies; Being a Hithertoe Unpublyshed Narrative of Conversation Betweene Master Francois Rabelais, the Vvitty Knight Don Quixote, and Some Others by Fryar Yordanus. London, Privatlie prynted for the Comstock Societie, [1914]. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Rabelaisian Fancies (for revision). n.p., 1920s(?).; ca. 20 leaves, in composition notebook. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Introduction., 4 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 39, Folder 3)
      With this: mockup of title page. 1 item (1 leaf).
    - A lettere from Terra Del Fuogo [sic]., 8 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Rabelaisian Phancies. A Narrative of Conversations Between Master Francis Rabelais, the Witty Don Quixote & Others. By Fryar Yordanus. Gardener at the Abbey of Thelene, etc. Newly edited and corrected by John Howe, M.A. Together with the one surviving epistle of the Familiar Letters, written by Fryar Yordanus from Tierra del Fuego, & describing Moralities of that strange land. Birmingham, The University Press, 1933. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - The Road I Came; Some Recollections and Reflections Concerning Changes in American Life and Manners Since 1890 by Paul Jordan Smith. Caldwell, Idaho, The Caxton Printers Limited, 1960. (Box 39)
    - First draft. [Los Angeles,., 1957]; ca. 100 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - First draft (carbon) uncorrected [Los Angeles, 1957].; ca. 125 leaves, typescript carbon. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Corrected draft (partial), [Los Angeles, 1957].; ca. 95 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Original typescript manuscript. Los Angeles, 1957(?).; ca. 600 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript. Los Angeles, ca. 600 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 40, Folder 1)
      With this: writing tablet containing notes on manuscript corrections. 8 leaves, Holograph.
    - Corrected carbon manuscript. Los Angeles, ca. 310 leaves, typescript carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Corrected carbon manuscript. [Los Angeles, 1957].; ca. 330 leaves, typescript carbon with holograph corrections. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Acknowledgements., 3 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Table of contents., 1 leaf, typescript carbon. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Index., 17 leaves, Holograph. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Corrections and notes., ca. 50 leaves, including 10 leaves, in writing tablet. Typescript, typescript carbon and holograph. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Advertisements, 1959-1960.; 8 items. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Clipping, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. v.p., 1958-1959.; 5 items (8 leaves, 3 envelopes). (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Material Relating to Paul Jordan Smith's Hoax on the Modern Art World
  Mr. Smith founded the Disumbrationist school of art in 1924 to protest criticism of his wife's (Sarah Bixby Smith) traditional paintings. Under the pseudonym Pavel Jerdanowitch, he earned critical acclaim for his modernist paintings throughout the art world.
  Original oil paintings are located in the Department of Special Collections, UCLA (Catalogued Orig. 99)
  - Catalogs and journals., 1913-1927.; 8 items. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Description of Disumbrationist School., 2 leaves, typescript. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Descriptions of paintings for catalog., 63 leaves, typescript. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, n.d., 1924-1926.; 15 items. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1930.; 12 items. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1953.; 11 items. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Ephemera., 26 items. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    For clippings, see folders 17-18.
- Manuscript Material
  - Mr. Duffins Goes in for Art. [Los Angeles, n.d.].; 9 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - For Art's Sake. Los Angeles, n.d.; 24 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 42, Folder 9)
    Also known as: Mr. Duffins goes in for art.
  - For Art's Sake. [Los Angeles], n.d.; 22 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Mr. Duffins goes in for art. Los Angeles, n.d.; 37 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Mr. Duffins goes in for art. Los Angeles, n.d.; 31 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. With blue cover. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Mr. Duffins goes in for art. [Los Angeles], n.d.; 30 leaves, typescript. With orange cover. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Negatives and negative photostats., 10 items. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Zinc plate for reproduction of Aspiration by Pavel Jerdanowitch. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Sketches and watercolors., 2 items. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Clippings., ca. 50 items/folder. (Box 42, Folder 17-18)
  - L'art contemporain. Livre d'or (Premiére série) Avec une préface de M. Gabriel Moussac. Paris, Éditions de la Revue du vrai et du beau, Jerdanowitch, pp.85-86., 1926. (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Manuscript Material By Others
  - [Anonymous] [History of Chattanooga, 1865-1880]. Tampa, Florida, [1935].; 25 leaves, and envelope. Typescript. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Browne, Lewis, 1897-. Hot Aryan. n.p., n.d.; 5 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Nixon, W.M. Chattanooga n.p, 1865-1880. n.d.; 9 leaves, typescript. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark, Islandia, the wisdom of the heart. Los Angeles, 1906-. 1956.; 15 leaves, Mimeo. (Box 43, Folder 5)
    With this: Letter of transmittal from Powell to Paul Jordan Smith. Los Angeles, 1956. 1 leaf, Holograph.
  - Starnes, DeWitt Talmage, 1888-. Correspondence and recollections of [Chattanooga] v.p., 1965.; 18 leaves, and envelope. Photocopy and mimeograph. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Vodrey, Joseph Kelly. [Arthur Machen] n.p., 1963(?).; 14 leaves, Photocopy. (Box 43, Folder 7)
- Books Inscribed to Paul Jordan Smith
  See also: Box 49
  - --Kirkbride, Ronald. Winds, Blow Gently. New York, Frederick Hall, 1945. (Box 43)
  - --Neider, Charles. The White Citadel. New York, Twayne Publishers, [c, 1954]. (Box 43)
  - --Rocker, Rudolf. The Six. Los Angeles, Rocker Publication Committee, [1938]. (Box 43)
  - --Schwartz, Harry W. This Book Collecting Racket. Chicago, Normandie House, Foreword by Paul Jordan Smith., 1934. (Box 43)
  - --Sinclair, Upton. The Brass Check. Pasadena, [Upton Sicnalir], 1919. (Box 43)
- Ephemera
  - Articles and periodicals by or concerning Paul Jordan Smith., 27 items. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Articles and periodicals by or concerning Paul Jordan Smith., 27 items. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Articles and periodicals inscribed to Paul Jordan Smith., 5 items. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - The family, vol.7 no.8 (). Contains article by Paul Jordan Smith's wife, Dorothy E. Wysor, How can we interpret social work to the public, pp.248-250., December 1926 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous literary articles collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 5 items. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous literary articles collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 26 items. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous literary articles collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 32 items. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous literary articles collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 14 items. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Book advertisements., 12 items. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 18 items. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 15 items. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Ephemera collected by Paul Jordan Smith., 27 items. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Ephemera concerning Emory and Henry College. Bristol, Virginia, 1963.; 2 items. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Heaver for Congress. Beverly Hills, 1960.; 3 items. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Ephemera concerning lectures given by Paul Jordan Smith., 35 items. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notices for Paul Jordan Smith. Los Angeles, (?)., 1920s; ca. 100 items. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Ephemera concerning the University of Chattanooga, Tennessee., 7 items. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - World War II ephemera., 14 items. (Box 45, Folder 10)
- Personal Material
  - American Kennel Club., 2 items. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Auto insurance., 2 items. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Bookplates., 6 items. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Christmas cards and lists., ca. 50 items. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Clippings by or concerning Paul Jordan Smith., 12 items. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Clubs., 6 items. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Eulogy for Lawrence Tibbett, given by Paul Jordan Smith at Forest Lawn. Los Angeles, 1960.; 3 leaves, typescript. (Box 46, Folder 7)
    With this Poems by Grace (Mrs. Lawrence) Tibbett. 9 leaves, typescript.
  - Family history., 5 items. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Heresy charge. Ephemera related to Paul Jordan Smith while minister of the First Universalist Church, Kansas City, Missouri, assistant lecturer of the Independent Religious Society, Chicago, manager of the Humanist Lyceum Bureau of Chicago and minister of the Chicago Lawn Congregational Church, v.p., 1909-1914.; 13 items. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, v.p., 1910-1916.; 27 items. (Box 46, Folder 10)
    These chiefly concern charges of heresy faced by Paul Jordan Smith while minister of the First Universalist Church, Kansas City, Missouri. Differences of theological interpretation were the cause of the charges. Mr. Smith later resigned to take the position of assistant lecturer of the Independent Religious Society in Chicago.
  - Horoscope of Paul Jordan Smith by Professor C. Irvin Althouse. Los Angeles, 1919(?).; 22 leaves, typescript. (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Identification cards., 32 items. (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Inventory of the library of Havelock Ellis., 19 leaves, typescript. (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Inventories, checklists of the library of Paul Jordan Smith., 45 leaves, typescript. (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Letter to the Los Angeles Times by Paul Jordan Smith. Los Angeles, 1966.; 2 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 46, Folder 15)
    Published by the Los Angeles Times, September 7, 1966.
  - Letterhead. Paul Jordan Smith's stationery., 13 leaves. (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Names and addresses., 9 leaves, typescript and holograph. (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Obituaries, 1971.; 4 items. (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - People's Council of America. Los Angeles, 1910s(?).; 5 items. Letterhead. (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Portraits., 3 items. (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Receipts., 7 items. (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Resurrection at eighty by Paul Jordan Smith. Long Beach, 1965.; 1 leaf, typescript. (Box 46, Folder 22)
    For Thanksgiving party, 1965.
  - Thanksgiving--The Historical Approach [by Paul Jordan Smith]. Los Angeles, 1955.; 6 leaves, typescript. (Box 46, Folder 23)
    Talk given by Paul Jordan Smith at the home of A. Maxson Smith, Los Angeles, November 24, 1955, at the Smith family Thanksgiving dinner.
  - Travel., 6 items. (Box 46, Folder 24)
- Memorabilia
  - Address books, memoranda books, billfold., 8 items. (Box 47)
  - Photos and postcards, v.p, v.d.; ca. 75 items. (Box 47)
  - Zinc plates. Illustration (facsimile of Robert Burton's copy of Purchas) and design from For the Love of Books by Paul Jordan Smith. New York, Oxford University Press, 1934.; 2 items. (Box 47)
  - Sketch of Julian Hawthorne, 1846-1934, by Sarah Bixby Smith. [Los Angeles], April 1926.; 1 item. Pen and ink. (Box 47)
- Additions
  - Business card., 1 item. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Paul Jordan Smith. Rare books and first editions. The Book. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Chamber. Unity Pegues Book Shop. 6417 Hollywood Boulevard. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Mosher, Fredric J. Freedom of Book Selection. Chicago, American Library Association, Paul Jordan Smith--The Responsibility of the Literary Critic: Some Indirections for Selecting Good Books, pp.75-89., 1954. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Zeitlin, Jake. [Eulogy for] Paul Jordan Smith. Los Angeles, June 21, 1971.; 4 leaves, photocopy of typescript. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - The First Unitarian Church of Berkeley, California. n.p. [Berkeley] (?) Exterior and interior views of the church. Photographs by Ken Reeves., 1940s; 18pp. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    Box 48: room to add.
  - Scrapbook, v.p, Reviews of books by Paul Jordan Smith and related material. Many clippings are loose, tucked into the back of the scrapbook., 1906-1962. (Box 53)
    With this Copy of Writers' Markets & Methods. vol.49 no.3, (January 1943), containing interview with PJS by Bernice Cornell, pp.7, 19.
- Books Inscribed to Paul Jordan Smith
  See also: Box 43
  - --Page, Elizabeth. The Tree Of Liberty. New York, Toronto: Farrar & Rinehart, Incorporated [c, 1939]; 985pp. Dustjacket. Inscribed to Paul Jordan Smith from the author, on half-title page. (Box 49)
    Additions, L. Hatayama, October 1986.
    Unprocessed material, gift of Wilbur Jordan Smith, 1982-1986.
  - Manuscripts and related material. (Box 50)
    - -From Hidden Springs. (Box 50)
    - -The Road I Came. (Box 50)
  - Manuscripts. (Box 51)
    - -The Discovery Book of Verse. (Box 51)